[
    {
        "cell_ids": [
            1
        ],
        "question": "What does the notebook describe in terms of using collaborative filtering?",
         "answer": "The notebook describes collaborative filtering using the Movielens datasets to recommend movies to users.",
        "task": "Recommendation Systems",
         "skill": "Collaborative Filtering"
    },
     {
        "cell_ids": [
           2
         ],
        "question": "What are the three data files that are loaded from the MovieLens dataset?",
         "answer": "ratings.csv, tags.csv, movies.csv",
        "task": "Basic Data Analysis",
         "skill": "Basic Data Analysis"
    },
    {
        "cell_ids": [
           2
        ],
        "question": "What is the main goal of the collaborative filtering implementation?",
         "answer": "to be able to predict ratings for movies a user has not yet watched.",
       "task": "Recommendation Systems",
       "skill": "Collaborative Filtering"
    },
    {
        "cell_ids": [
           1,2
         ],
        "question": "What is the main idea behind matrix factorization for recommendations?",
         "answer": "Map user ID to a \"user vector\" via an embedding matrix, Map movie ID to a \"movie vector\" via an embedding matrix, Compute the dot product between the user vector and movie vector, to obtain the a match score between the user and the movie (predicted rating), Train the embeddings via gradient descent using all known user-movie pairs.",
        "task": "Recommendation Systems",
        "skill": "Matrix Factorization"
    },
     {
        "cell_ids": [
            7
         ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of 'is_fav' column in the user_rating table?",
       "answer": "Initializing a dummy variable for future use",
      "task": "Basic Data Analysis",
      "skill": "Basic Data Analysis"
    },
    {
        "cell_ids": [
           11
         ],
        "question": "What is being analyzed to choose K?",
        "answer": "demographics of Books and Users",
        "task":"Customer Segmentation",
        "skill":"K-means Clustering"
    },
    {
       "cell_ids": [
            86
        ],
        "question": "What are the shapes of data before and after removing non-valid users/books?",
       "answer": "shape before cleaning: (1149780, 3) shape after cleaning: (1003113, 3)",
      "task":"Basic Data Analysis",
       "skill":"Basic Data Analysis"
    },
    {
        "cell_ids": [
            87
         ],
        "question": "After filtering, how many ratings are considered as a user 'likes' a book?",
        "answer": "304838",
         "task": "Recommendation Systems",
         "skill": "Collaborative Filtering"
    },
    {
        "cell_ids": [
           92
        ],
        "question": "What is the shape of the data after PCA is applied?",
        "answer": "(4790, 3)",
        "task": "Principal Component Analysis",
         "skill": "SVD"
    },
    {
       "cell_ids": [
            94
        ],
        "question": "How many clusters are used in the final clustering model?",
        "answer": "4",
       "task": "Customer Segmentation",
       "skill": "K-means Clustering"
    }
]